Guide to the Evsey D. Domar Papers, 1939-1995 and undated (bulk 1957-1989)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Evsey D. Domar papers 1939-1995 and undated, bulk 1957-1989
Domar, Evsey D.
27.5 linear feet Extent: 20,625 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00317
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Parts of the collection are restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The papers were received as a bequest from the estate of Evsey Domar in 1997.
Biographical Note
1914, April 16 Born in Lodz, Russia (now Poland), given name was Joshua Domashevitsky
1939 B.A., University of California at Los Angeles
1941 M.A., Mathematical Statistics, University of Michigan
1943 M.A., Economics, Harvard University
1943-1946 Economist, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System
1944 Published Proportional income taxation and risk-taking, with R. A. Musgrave, in Quarterly Journal of Economics
1946 Married Carola Rosenthal
1946-1947 Assistant Professor of Economics, Carnegie Institute of Technology
1947 Ph.D. Economics, Harvard University.
1947-1948 Assistant Professor in the Dept. of Economics and Research Associate in the Cowles Commission, University of Chicago
1948-1955 Associate Professor of Political Economy, Johns Hopkins University
1949-1951 Director of Russian Studies, Operations Research Office, Johns Hopkins University
1951-1955 Visiting Associate Professor, Russian Institute, Columbia University
1951-1981 Consultant, Rand Corporation
1954-1958 Consultant of Foreign Studies, Research Fellowship Program, The Ford Foundation
1955-1958 Professor of Political Economy, Johns Hopkins University
1956-1959 Consultant, Brookings Institute
1957 Published Essays in the Theory of Economic Growth
1958-1972 Professor of Economics, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
1963- Editorial Board, American Economist
1961-1962 Consultant, Institute of Defense Analysis
1966 Published The Soviet collective farm as a producer cooperative, American Economic Review
1967-1969 Consultant, National Science Foundation
1970 Published The causes of slavery or serfdom: a hypothesis, Journal of Economic History
1972-1984 Ford International Professor of Economics, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
1976-1982 Editorial Board, Journal of Comparative Economics
1984 Retired from MIT
1986-1990 Visiting Professor, Brandeis University
1989 Published Capitalism, Socialism, and Serfdom
Collection Overview
The papers of Evsey Domar span the years 1939 through 1995, with the bulk of the papers being dated between 1957 and 1989. The collection consists chiefly of professional correspondence between Domar and his colleagues, with smaller groups of materials consisting of writings; research materials; printed materials; speeches and lectures; and course materials relating to Domar's teaching career. Although Domar was interested in a wide range of subjects in the fields of economics and political science, the papers in this collection chiefly address his work on serfdom and slavery, particularly in Russia; the economics of socialist systems of government; the economics of agriculture; and theories of productivity and efficiency. Other minor topics include macroeconomics; the economies of Yugoslavia and Lithuania; value-added tax systems; economic development, and growth in general, and the American economy.
The Correspondence Series consists of professional correspondence concerning recommendations, papers, publishing, trip planning and reports, invitation responses, and other academic affairs. Frequently Domar exchanged comments on papers and other writings with fellow colleagues and former students. Important correspondents include Don Patinkin, Mark Perlman, Allan Brown, Alexander Gerschenkron, Lauchlin Currie, Alvin Hansen, Joan Robinson, and many others.
The Research Materials Series contains papers documenting Domar's research on serfdom and slavery (particularly in Russia); productivity and efficiency; value-added taxes; and other topics. Several papers discuss the economies of Yugoslavia and Lithuania. Includes many graphs and tables relating to Domar's published and unpublished work. There are very few papers by other individuals.
The Printed Materials Series is made up of mostly hardcover books from Domar's personal library. Most are editions or translations of his own published works, but there are several works by other authors. Includes microfilm of 1904 Russian work on unknown subject matter, and 1980 translation of 1861 Russian work on serfdom in Russia.
The Course Materials Series contains lecture notes and other materials related to Domar's extensive teaching career in economics. Two notebooks from 1939 and 1940 reveal aspects of his student years
Subject Headings
Agriculture -- Economic aspects; Slavery-Economic aspects; Serfdom-Russia; Russia -- Economic conditions; Economics -- Study and teaching; Comparative economics; Socialism-Economic aspects; Russia-History; Economists -- United States -- Correspondence; Economic development; Value-added tax; Macroeconomics; Patinkin, Don; Perlman, Mark; Currie, Lauchlin Bernard; Gerschenkron, Alexander; Hansen, Alvin Harvey, 1887-; Brown, Alan A.; Robinson, Joan, 1903-; Domar, Evsey D.
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence, 1940s-1990s and undated
  Chiefly professional correspondence covering a wide array of topics, including recommendations, discussions of papers, publishing, trip planning and reports, invitation responses, and other academic affairs. Arranged in alphabetical order. Folders with a single letter as a heading (e.g., A-General) contain general correspondence separately filed by Domar, possibly in his home files.
  - A-General (Box 1)
  - Aa-Al (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Aa-Al (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - A-D (Box 1)
  - Am-Az (Box 1)
  - American Council of Learned Societies: Trip Report and Correspondence (Box 1)
  - American Economist: Short Speech and Correspondence (Box 1)
  - American Economic Association (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - American Economic Review: Review of Papers and Correspondence (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Society (Box 1)
  - Association for Comparative Economics (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Association for Comparative Economic Studies (Box 1)
  - Association for the Study of Soviet-Type Economics: Papers and Correspondence (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Albert Ando (Box 1)
  - Australia (Box 1)
  - B-General (Box 1)
  - B-Bk (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - B-Bk (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Bl-Br (1 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Bl-Br (2 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Bl-Br (3 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Br-Bz (1 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Br-Bz (2 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Br-Bz (3 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Battelle Memorial Institute (Box 1)
  - Bella Balassa: Discussion Paper by Domar (Box 1)
  - Batelle Memorial Institute Paper (Box 1)
  - Abram Bergson (Box 1)
  - Joseph Berliner (Box 1)
  - B.H. Blackwell LTD. (Box 1)
  - Herbert Block Paper (Box 1)
  - Diren Bodenhorn (Box 1)
  - Bogota, Colombia (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Bogota, Colombia (2 of 2) (Box 2)
  - Boston College, 1967-1974 (Box 2)
  - Brandeis University (Box 2)
  - Brazil: Letters and Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Brigham Young University (Box 2)
  - University of British Colombia (Box 2)
  - Brookings Institution (Box 2)
  - Alan Brown, 1965-1975 (Box 2)
  - Brown University, 1962-1978 (Box 2)
  - Helena Brus: Evaluation (Box 2)
  - Ca-Cm (1 of 3) (Box 2)
  - Ca-Cm (2 of 3) (Box 2)
  - Ca-Cm (3 of 3) (Box 2)
  - E. Cary Brown, 1956-1972 (Box 2)
  - Cm-Cz (1 of 2) (Box 2)
  - Cm-Cz (2 of 2) (Box 2)
  - University of California Berkley (Box 2)
  - University of California Davis: Appraisal Letters (Box 2)
  - University of California Los Angeles (Box 2)
  - University of California Santa Barbara (Box 2)
  - University of California Santa Cruz (Box 2)
  - University of California Other Campuses (Box 2)
  - University of California Press (Box 2)
  - Committee on Comparative Urban Economics (Box 2)
  - Dominion Bureau of Statistics Canada (Box 2)
  - Alan Carlin (Box 2)
  - Allan M. Carter Paper (Box 2)
  - Center for the Advanced Study of Behavioral Sciences: Correspondence and Miscellaneous (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Central Intelligence Agency (Box 2)
  - Janet Chapman: Paper Review by Domar (Box 2)
  - Hg-Scheong Cheung (Box 2)
  - University of Chicago (Box 2)
  - University of Chicago Press (Box 2)
  - China Correspondence After the Trip (Box 2)
  - China Correspondence Before and During the Trip (Box 2)
  - John Chipman (Box 2)
  - Carl Crist (Box 2)
  - University of Cincinnati (Box 2)
  - Claremont Graduate School and CAL Tech (Box 2)
  - Clark University (Box 2)
  - David Collander Interview with Domar and Paper (Box 2)
  - Colby College (Box 2)
  - University of Colorado and Economics Institute (Box 2)
  - Colombia University (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Colombia University (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with China (Box 3)
  - Committee on Ways and Means (Box 3)
  - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils (Box 3)
  - Conference on Research of Income and Wealth (Box 3)
  - Lauchlin Currie (Box 3)
  - Bruno Cutilli: Foreign Language Paper and Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Czechoslovakia (Box 3)
  - D-General (Box 3)
  - Da-Dm (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Da-Dm (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Dn-Dz (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Dn-Dz (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Laura D'Andrea: Papers and Recommendations (Box 3)
  - Michael Dohan: Thesis Outline and Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Dinko Dubravcic Paper (Box 3)
  - Duke University (Box 3)
  - Elizabeth Durbin: Paper and Correspondence (Box 3)
  - E-General (Box 3)
  - E (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - E (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Economic History Association (Box 3)
  - European History Conference in Aix, 1962 (Box 3)
  - The Economic Journal (Box 3)
  - Economic Society: Correspondence and Paper (Box 3)
  - Alexander Eckstein (Box 3)
  - Warren Eason (Box 3)
  - Alexander Erlich (Box 3)
  - Robert Eisner (Box 3)
  - Herbert Evans (Box 3)
  - F-General (Box 3)
  - Fa-Fm (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Fa-Fm (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Fn-Fz (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Fn-Fz (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Soloman Fabricant (Box 3)
  - Federal Reserve Bank of New York (Box 3)
  - Federal Reserve Board (Box 3)
  - George Feiwal (Box 3)
  - David Felix: Statement of Vietnam (Box 3)
  - Finland (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation: Correspondence and Proposals (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation: Correspondence and Proposals (2 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Fordham University: Site Visit Report (Box 3)
  - Foreign Visitors and Economics (Box 3)
  - Margery Foster (Box 3)
  - Four Continent Book Corporation (Box 3)
  - France (Box 3)
  - Edward Fried Report (Box 3)
  - G-General (Box 3)
  - G (1 of 3) (Box 3)
  - G (2 of 3) (Box 3)
  - G (3 of 3) (Box 4)
  - Joshua S. Gans (Box 4)
  - Germany (Box 4)
  - Greg Grossman (Box 4)
  - Guggenheim Foundation: Evaluations (Box 4)
  - Alexander Gerschenkron (Box 4)
  - H (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - H (2 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Ha-He (1 of 3) (Box 4)
  - Ha-He (2 of 3) (Box 4)
  - Ha-He (3 of 3) (Box 4)
  - Hf-Hz (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Hf-Hz (2 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Alvin Hansen (Box 4)
  - Michael J. Hare: Paper and Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Seymour Harris (Box 4)
  - Harvard University Press (Box 4)
  - Harvard University: Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Harvard University: Russian Research Center Papers and Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Oli Gawrylyshyn: Recommendation Letters and Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Derek Healey (Box 4)
  - W. P. Hogan (Box 4)
  - F. D. Holzman (Box 4)
  - University of Hong Kong: External Evaluation (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - University of Hong Kong: External Evaluation (2 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Branko Horvat: Correspondence and Papers (Box 4)
  - Bert Hoselitz (Box 4)
  - H. D. Huggins (Box 4)
  - Hungary (Box 4)
  - Holland Hunter (Box 4)
  - I (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - I (2 of 2) (Box 4)
  - University of Illinois and University of Illinois Chicago (Box 4)
  - Indiana University: Correspondence and External Review Papers (Box 4)
  - Institute for Defense Analysis (Box 4)
  - Institute for International Education (Box 4)
  - International Association for Research on Income and Wealth (Box 4)
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (Box 4)
  - International Economic Association (Box 4)
  - International Research and Exchanges Board (Box 4)
  - Inter-University Committee on Russian Travel Grants (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Inter-University Committee on Russian Travel Grants (2 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Israel (1 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Israel (2 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Dwight Israelsen (Box 5)
  - J-General (Box 5)
  - J (Box 5)
  - Senator Henry Jackson (Box 5)
  - Japan (Box 5)
  - John Hopkins University (Box 5)
  - Joint Committee on Slavic Studies (Box 5)
  - Joint Economic Committee: Testimony and Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Journal of Comparative Economics (Box 5)
  - Journal of Economic History (Box 5)
  - Journal of Social and Biological Structures (Box 5)
  - Journal of Political Economy (Box 5)
  - Karl Jungenfelt (Box 5)
  - K-General (Box 5)
  - Ka-Kel (1 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Ka-Kel (2 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Kem-Kz (1 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Kem-Kz (2 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Edward Kane: Correspondence and Papers (Box 5)
  - Norman Kaplan (Box 5)
  - Daniel Kazmer (Box 5)
  - Murray Kemp (Box 5)
  - John W. Kendrick (Box 5)
  - Senator Edward Kennedy (Box 5)
  - T. S. Khachaturov: Correspondence and Papers (1 of 2) (Box 5)
  - T. S. Khachaturov: Correspondence and Papers (2 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Boris Khazanon (Box 5)
  - Charles Kinderberger (Box 5)
  - Emine Kiray: Recommendation Letters (1 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Emine Kiray: Recommendation Letters (2 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Simon Kuznets: Correspondence and Bibliography (Box 5)
  - Oldrich Kyn (Box 5)
  - L-General (Box 5)
  - La-Le (1 of 2) (Box 5)
  - La-Le (2 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Lf-Lz (Box 5)
  - Letters to the Editor (Box 5)
  - Herbert Levine: Draft Proposal for the Institute for the Study of the Soviet Union (Box 5)
  - M-General (Box 5)
  - Ma-Md (1 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Ma-Md (2 of 2) (Box 5)
  - Me-Mz (1 of 3) (Box 5)
  - Me-Mz (2 of 3) (Box 5)
  - Me-Mz (3 of 3) (Box 5)
  - MC and MAC (Box 5)
  - Michael Manove: Paper and Correspondence (Box 5)
  - McGraw Hill Book Company (Box 5)
  - University of Maine (Box 5)
  - Machinery and Allied Products Institute: Paper and Correspondence (Box 6)
  - David W. Maxwell (Box 6)
  - James A. Maxwell (Box 6)
  - Michael Mazur: Thesis Proposal and Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Merrill Center for Economics: Conference on the Economics of Education (Box 6)
  - Lloyd Metzler (Box 6)
  - University of Michigan (1 of 2) (Box 6)
  - University of Michigan (2 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Middlebury College (Box 6)
  - Michigan State University (Box 6)
  - Milena Jovicic (Box 6)
  - James Miller (Box 6)
  - University of Minnesota (Box 6)
  - John Montias (Box 6)
  - Basil Moore (Box 6)
  - Amotz Morag: Paper and Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Selma Mushkin (Box 6)
  - Richard Musgrave: Bibliography of Articles on the Economics of Taxation and Correspondence (Box 6)
  - N-General (Box 6)
  - Na-Nem (Box 6)
  - Nem-Nz (1 of 3) (Box 6)
  - Nem-Nz (2 of 3) (Box 6)
  - Nem-Nz (3 of 3) (Box 6)
  - Tamas Nagy (Box 6)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research: Conference Minutes and Correspondence (1 of 2) (Box 6)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research: Conference Minutes and Correspondence (2 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Egon Neuberger (Box 6)
  - State University of New York at Albany (1 of 2) (Box 6)
  - State University of New York at Albany (2 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Jurg Niehans (Box 6)
  - Northwestern University (Box 6)
  - O-General (Box 6)
  - O (1 of 2) (Box 6)
  - O (2 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Oklahoma City University (Box 6)
  - Anders Olgaard (Box 6)
  - Mancur Olson (Box 6)
  - Omicron Delta Epsilon (1 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Omicron Delta Epsilon (2 of 2) (Box 6)
  - University of Oregon (Box 6)
  - Oriental Research Partners (Box 6)
  - Osterwell Prize in Economics (Box 6)
  - P-General (Box 6)
  - Pa-Ph (1 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Pa-Ph (2 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Pi-Pz (1 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Pi-Pz (2 of 2) (Box 6)
  - Mary Painter (Box 6)
  - William Parker (Box 6)
  - Don Patikin (Box 6)
  - Felipe Pazos (Box 6)
  - Austin Peck (Box 7)
  - University of Pennsylvania (Box 7)
  - Edith Penrose (Box 7)
  - Mark Perlman (Box 7)
  - Boris Pesek (Box 7)
  - John Pettengill (Box 7)
  - Philippines (Box 7)
  - Anna Polorna (Box 7)
  - Richard Portes (Box 7)
  - M. M. Postan (Box 7)
  - Princeton University (Box 7)
  - O. Prochazka (Box 7)
  - Stanfor Pulrang: Correspondence and Paper (Box 7)
  - Q (Box 7)
  - Quarterly Journal of Economics: Referee Comments, Proposals, and Correspondence (Box 7)
  - R-General (Box 7)
  - Ra-Re (Box 7)
  - Re-Rz (1 of 3) (Box 7)
  - Re-Rz (2 of 3) (Box 7)
  - Re-Rz (3 of 3) (Box 7)
  - The RAND Corporation, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - Review of Economics and Statistics (Box 7)
  - University of Rhode Island (Box 7)
  - Rice University (Box 7)
  - Joan Robinson (Box 7)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 7)
  - Spain and Portugal Visit, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Robert V. Roosa (Box 7)
  - Rochester Conference on the Application of Mathematical Methods to Soviet Economic Planning, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Romania (Box 7)
  - Stephan Royez (Box 7)
  - Rutgers University (Box 7)
  - S-General (Box 7)
  - Soviet Union (Box 7)
  - Frank Spooner (Box 7)
  - Nicolas Spuler (Box 7)
  - Ivan Mateev Stefanov (Box 7)
  - The Stockholm School of Economics (Box 7)
  - Vladimir Stoikov: Paper and Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Paul Streeten (Box 7)
  - Subcommittee on the Grants of the Joint Committee on Slavic Studies (Box 7)
  - Barry E. Supple (Box 7)
  - Kund Erik Svendsen (Box 7)
  - Sweden: Correspondence with Various Professors (Box 7)
  - Swedish Royal Academy of Sciences (Box 7)
  - Syracuse University (Box 7)
  - T-General (Box 7)
  - T (1 of 3) (Box 7)
  - T (2 of 3) (Box 7)
  - T (3 of 3) (Box 7)
  - Peter Temin (Box 7)
  - University of Toronto (Box 7)
  - Tulane University (Box 7)
  - Pavel Turcan (Box 7)
  - Turkey (Box 7)
  - U (Box 7)
  - United Malayan Banking Corporation (Box 7)
  - United Nations (Box 7)
  - Department of Education Conference: Various Documents and Correspondence, 1964 (Box 8)
  - US Government Agencies (Box 8)
  - V (Box 8)
  - Vanderbilt University (Box 8)
  - W-We (1 of 2) (Box 8)
  - W-We (2 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Wh-Wz (1 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Wh-Wz (2 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Martin Weitzman: Cowles Commission Paper and Correspondence (Box 8)
  - Wellesley College (Box 8)
  - University of Western Ontario (Box 8)
  - Wolf's Manuscript (Box 8)
  - Woodrow Wilson Fellowships (Box 8)
  - Yale University (1 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Yale University (2 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Yugoslavia (Box 8)
  - X, Y, and Z (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
- Research Materials, 1944-1995 and undated (Box 8)
  Papers documenting Domar's research in serfdom and slavery (particularly in Russia), comparative productivity and efficiency, value-added taxes, and other topics. Includes many computations and charts relating to Domar's published and unpublished work. Also contains series of notecards on various subjects.
  Files are in Domar's original order.
  - "Index Number Tournament": Computations (Box 9)
  - "Index Number Tournament" (Box 9)
  - Index of Industrial Production (Box 9)
  - "Index Number Tournament": Manuscript (Box 9)
  - "Index Number Tournament": Derivations (Box 9)
  - "Soviet Postwar Economic Growth and Capital Labor Substitution," Walter l. Weitzman (Box 9)
  - "Index Number Tournament": Manuscript, 1966 (Box 9)
  - "On the Measurement of Comparative Efficiency" (1 of 2) (Box 9)
  - "On the Measurement of Comparative Efficiency" (2 of 2) (Box 9)
  - East-West Trade (Box 9)
  - "Comparative Productivity and Efficiency in the USSR," Abram Bergson (Box 9)
  - "On Total Productivity and All That" (Box 9)
  - "Total Productivity and the Quality of Capital" (Box 9)
  - "Efficiency of the Soviet Economy," Joseph Berliner (Box 9)
  - On the Measurement of Technological Progress (Box 9)
  - How to Compare the B Index in One Lesson (Box 9)
  - Reflections on Economic Development (Box 9)
  - Technological Progress Project (Box 9)
  - Production Functions (Box 9)
  - Notes on Productivity (Box 9)
  - Productivity Study (Box 9)
  - Review of Kendrick's Article (Box 9)
  - Slavery Papers (6 folders) (Box 9)
  - "The Causes of Slavery: A Hypothesis" (draft copy) (Box 9)
  - Economic Development Institute Lectures, 1965-1969 (1 of 2) (Box 9)
  - Economic Development Institute Lectures, 1965-1969 (2 of 2) (Box 9)
  - Bergson's Table (Box 9)
  - Lectures Given in England, 1952-1953 (Box 10)
  - Education and Research: General (Box 10)
  - Contributions of Federal Expenditures to Economic Growth and Stability: Congressional Joint Committee on the Economic Report, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Lectures on the Soviet Economy, 1957-1986 (1 of 2) (Box 10)
  - Lectures on the Soviet Economy, 1957-1986 (2 of 2) (Box 10)
  - Soviet Economic Development (Box 10)
  - Lectures on Russian Serfdom, 1988 (Box 10)
  - Chayan Book Reviews (Box 10)
  - Bensosan-Butt's Book Review (Box 10)
  - Price and Wage Policy: Joint Congressional Committee, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Feldman's Model (Box 10)
  - CORFU Paper on Capital Coefficients (Box 10)
  - Mt. Holyoke Lectures (Box 10)
  - Lecture: "On the State of the American Economy," 1974 (Box 10)
  - Lecture: "The Problem of Economic Growth: To Grow or Not to Grow" (Box 10)
  - Lessons from Growth Models, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Cowles Commission Discussion Paper, 1948 (Box 10)
  - Comments on Professor Kuznet's Paper: "International Differences in Capital Foundation and Financing," 1953 (Box 10)
  - Lecture: Economics and the Modern University, 1961 (Box 10)
  - Lecture: "The Rise of Meritocracy," 1971 (Box 10)
  - "Poor Mr. Nixon" (Box 10)
  - Various Papers (Box 10)
  - Trip to USSR, 1960 (Box 10)
  - USSR Travel Notes (1 of 2) (Box 10)
  - USSR Travel Notes (2 of 2) (Box 10)
  - Soviet Materials on Economists (Box 10)
  - Soviet Teaching of Economics (Box 10)
  - Yugoslavia (Box 10)
  - USSR Miscellaneous Trip (1 of 2) (Box 10)
  - USSR Miscellaneous Trip (2 of 2) (Box 10)
  - "Depreciation, Replacement, and Growth Mathematical Appendix" (Box 10)
  - "The Effect of Foreign Investment on the Balance of Payments" (Box 10)
  - "The Case for Accelerated Depreciation: Mathematical Appendix" (Box 10)
  - Serfdom Defivations and Calculations and Notes (1 of 2) (Box 10)
  - Serfdom Defivations and Calculations and Notes (2 of 2) (Box 10)
  - Serfdom Graphs (Box 10)
  - "On the profitability on Russian Serfdom," 1984 (Miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - January 1984 (Draft Paper) (Box 10)
    - May 1984 (Draft Paper)` (Box 10)
    - 1984 (Legal Aspects) (Box 10)
  - Foreign Economic Development (Box 10)
  - Current Research (Box 10)
  - "Were Russian Serfs Overcharged for Their Land in 1861?:" Draft Copies and Notes (Box 11)
  - Model C Calculations (Box 11)
  - Serfdom: Russian Publications (4 folders) (Box 11)
  - Serfdom: Various Papers (1 of 2) (Box 11)
  - Serfdom: Various Papers (2 of 2) (Box 11)
  - Serfdom: Reprints of Russian Publications and Redemption Prices (Box 11)
  - Serfdom Sales Data (3 folders) (Box 11)
  - Serfdom Unweighted Regressions (Box 11)
  - Various Serfdom Tables (Box 11)
  - Serfdom: Redemption Prices Tables and Notes (Box 11)
  - On the Probability of Russian Serfdom: Statistical Appendix (Box 11)
  - Data List (Box 11)
  - On the Probability of Russian Serfdom (4 folders): (Box 11)
    - Appendix Calculations (Box 11)
    - Draft Comments (Box 11)
    - Original Charts (Box 11)
    - Correspondence and Notes (Box 11)
  - Effect of the Interest Rate (1 of 2) (Box 11)